Hyde Park, Boston, Mass. First Congregational Church of Hyde Park records, 1860-2003. RG4923
Congregational Library & Archives
- Membership and vital statistics, 1860-2003; 78 Folders; 6 Volumes
  - Membership cards, circa 1880-2000; 5 Box
    This subseries contains boxes of individual membership cards. These membership cards are seperated by membership at the time of the church's closing and members who left the church prior to that point.
    - Members: A-Z, circa 1880 (Box 13)
    - Past members: A-C, circa 1880-2000 (Box 13)
    - Past members: D-H, circa 1880-2000 (Box 14)
    - Past members: I-O, circa 1880-2000 (Box 15)
    - Past members: P-S, circa 1880-2000 (Box 16)
  - Baptisms, weddings, and funerals, 1948-2001; 4 Folders
    This subseries contains baptism, wedding, and funeral records from the church's founding through to its closure.
    - Deaths and marraiges, 1948-1976 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Baptismal records, 1976-2001 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Baptisms not recorded in roll book, 1980-1996 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Funeral certificates and obituaries, 1982-2001 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Membership lists, 1863-2003; 5 Folders; 6 Volumes
    This subseries contains lists and ledger books of members througout the church's history. It also includes a list of servicemen connected to the church though it is unclear if this record is from the first or second world war.
    - Roll book ledger, 1863-1980 (Box 17, Volume 3)
    - Roll book ledger, 1896-1996 (Box 17, Volume 2)
    - Roll book ledger, 1921-1998 (Box 17, Volume 1)
    - Roll book ledger, 1936-2002 (Box 19, Volume 3)
    - Membership list manuals, 1893-1946 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Membership list, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Membership lists, 1931-1948 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Register of members, 1935-2003 (Box 17, Volume 4)
    - Membership lists, 1957-2001 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Ruth Higbee membership records, 1954-1987 (Box 5, Volume 2)
    - Membership list of servicemen, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Membership materials, 1870-1925; 2 Folders
    This subseries contains additional materials related to church membership. This includes manuals for new members and publicity aimed at generating new members.
    - Membership manuals, 1870-1891 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Membership publicity, 1904-1925 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Church groups, 1871-1972; 21 Folders; 41 Volumes
  This series contains records of and pertaining to various church groups throughout the church's history. These records are largely administrative in nature and the series contains many bound volumes of such records.
  - Sunday school, 1871-1972; 8 Folders; 7 Volumes
    This subseries contains records created by and pertaining to the sunday school. This includes bound superintendant's record books, teacher administration materials, correspondence, and programs. The historical sketch from 1911 may be of particular interest to researchers.
    - Sunday school anniversary programs, 1871-1931 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Sunday school correspondence and reports, 1884-1920 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Sunday school programs, 1884-1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Teacher administration, 1884-1905 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Sunday school rally day, 1885-1926 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Sunday school anniversary bulletins, 1886-1909 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Superintendent's pocket record book, 1888-1889 (Box 4, Volume 12)
    - Sunday school class register, 1889 (Box 17, Volume 8)
    - Superintendent's record book, 1888-1889 (Box 4, Volume 16)
    - Superintendent's record book, 1889-1890 (Box 4, Volume 15)
    - Superintendent's record book, 1890-1891 (Box 4, Volume 14)
    - Superintendent's record book, 1891-1892 (Box 4, Volume 13)
    - Sunday school class register, 1890-1893 (Box 17, Volume 9)
    - Sunday school service programs, 1898-1931 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Sunday school historical sketch, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Heart and Hand Society, 1877-1884; 1 Volume
    This subseries contains the records of the Heart and Hand Society. It is contained in a single bound volume of treasurer records.
    - Heart and Hand society treasurer book, 1877-1884; 1 Volumes (Box 18, Volume 6)
  - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1884-1909; 11 Volumes; 1 Folders
    This subseries consists for records from the Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor. These records are largely contained within bound volumes of financial records and meeting minutes. It also contains some unbound materials including by-laws, correspondence and the group's consitution.
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors Membership, 1891-1895 (Box 6, Volume 1)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors membership, 1895-1902 (Box 6, Volume 2)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors list of members, 1902-1903 (Box 6, Volume 3)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors Lookout committee, 1892-1895 (Box 6, Volume 4)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors finance and executive, 1887-1888 (Box 6, Volume 5)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors by-laws, constitution, and programs, 1868-1909 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors, 1887-1888 (Box 6, Volume 6)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavors Lookout committee, 1889-1891 (Box 6, Volume 7)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1884-1889 (Box 17, Volume 10)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1898-1905 (Box 17, Volume 11)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1886-1896 (Box 17, Volume 12)
    - Young People's Society of Christian Endeavor, 1888-1895 (Box 17, Volume 13)
  - Junior Society of Christian Endeavor, 1889-1902; 3 Volumes
    This subseries consists of records from the Junior Society of Christian Endeavor. These include financial records and meeting minutes all contained within bound volumes.
    - Junior Society of Christian Endeavor, 1892-1896 (Box 17, Volume 5)
    - Junior Society of Christian Endeavor record book, 1889-1902 (Box 17, Volume 6)
    - Junior Society of Christian Endeavor record book, 1896-1899 (Box 17, Volume 7)
  - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1872-1939; 5 Volumes; 2 Folder
    This subseries contains records from the Auxiliary to the Woman's Board. These records are largely financial and meeting minutes contained in bound volumes. There are also two folders of unbound records including event programs and correspondence.
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1872-1882 (Box 18, Volume 16)
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1882-1888 (Box 18, Volume 17)
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1889-1895 (Box 18, Volume 18)
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1896-1902 (Box 18, Volume 19)
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1901-1939 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board record book, 1903-1918 (Box 18, Volume 20)
    - Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1911-1917 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Junior Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1894-1903; 1 Files
    This subseries consists of records of the Junior Auxiliary to the Woman's Board. These records include financial records, meeting minutes, and correspondence.
    - Junior Auxiliary to the Woman's Board, 1894-1903 (Box 18, Volume 14)
  - Woman's Home Missionary Union, 1885-1929; 4 Volumes; 1 Folders
    This subseries contains the records of the Woman's Home Missionary Union. These administrative records are contained in 4 bound volumes and one folder of unbound materials and include financial records, correspondence, and meeting minutes.
    - Woman's Home Missionary Union, 1883-1893 (Box 18, Volume 11)
    - Woman's Home Missionary Union, 1885-1896 (Box 18, Volume 10)
    - Woman's Home Missionary Union, 1893-1911 (Box 18, Volume 12)
    - Woman's Home Missionary Union, 1896-1917 (Box 18, Volume 13)
    - Woman's Home Missionary Union, 1915-1929; 1 Folders; 4 Volumes (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Maternal association, 1889-1906; 3 Volumes
    This subseries contains three bound volumes of records from the Maternal association. These records are administrative in nature.
    - Maternal association, 1889-1893 (Box 18, Volume 7)
    - Maternal association record book, 1893-1898 (Box 18, Volume 8)
    - Maternal association, 1898-1906 (Box 18, Volume 9)
  - Social committee, 1900-1924; 1 Volumes
    This subseries contains the records of the Social Committee. It is contained in a single bound volume of administrative records.
    - Social committee, 1900-1924 (Box 18, Volume 1)
  - Church Aid Society, 1905-1931; 3 Volumes; 1 Folders
    This subseries contains three bound volumes of administrative records and one unbound folder of correspondence, financial records, and meeting minutes from the Church Aid Society.
    - Church Aid Society record book, 1905-1916 (Box 18, Volume 3)
    - Church Aid Society record book, 1916-1925 (Box 18, Volume 4)
    - Church Aid Society, 1925-1930 (Box 18, Volume 5)
    - Church Aid Society, 1920-1931 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - New Church Building committee, 1884-1917; 5 Folders; 2 Volumes
    This subseries contains records pertaining to the building and the activities of the New Church Building committee. These records include financial records, correspondence, meeting minutes and reports, technical diagrams and blueprints, and appraisals.
    - Building and room dedications, 1884-1911 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - New Church Building committee, 1905-1909 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - New Church Building committee, 1906-1911 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - New Church Building committee record book, 1906 (Box 4, Volume 10)
    - New Church Building committee record book, 1906-1910 (Box 4, Volume 11)
    - New Church Building committee, 1909-1917 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Specifications of lighting fixtures, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - New church building blueprints, 1910 (Folder 2)
  - Committee on Military Affairs, 1917-1919; 1 Folders
    Administrative records from the Committee on Military Affairs.
    - Committee on Military Affairs, 1917-1919 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Woman's Union, 1917-1923; 1 Volumes
    This subseries contains the records of the Woman's Union. It is contained in a single bound volume of administrative records.
    - Woman's Union record book, 1917-1923 (Box 18, Volume 15)
  - Fairmont Circle, 1949-1954; 1 Folders
    This subseries contains a folder of meeting minutes from the Fairmont circle in 1951.
    - Fairmont circle meeting minutes, 1949-1954 (Box 18, Volume 2)
- Scrapbooks and photographs, 1900-2003; 5 Volumes; 8 Folders
  This series consists of photographs and scrapbooks. The photographs largely document the building at various times throughout its history. There are a number of scrapbooks of the photographs as well as a copy of the photograph scrapbook on CD. There is also a scrapbook of newspaper clippings related to the church.
  - Scrapbooks, 1900-1943; 5 Volumes; 1 Folders
    This subseries consists of scrapbooks of photographs and newspaper clippings. The photograph scrapbooks largely document the church building.
    - Building photo scrapbook, undated (Box 10, Volume 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1900-1913 (Box 19, Volume 1)
    - Newspaper clipping scrapbook, 1904-1907 (Box 19, Volume 2)
      Physical restrictions
      The condition of this unbound volume is extremely fragile. Staff assistance required for access.
    - Scrapbook, 1921-1926 (Box 20, Volume 1)
    - Building photograph scrapbook, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Scrapbook, 1937-1943 (Box 21, Volume 1)
  - Photographs, 1908-2003; 7 Folder
    This subseries consists of unbound photographs. There are also two CD copies of the photograph scrapbook. The photographs document and the building and a few people with connections to the church.
    - Building committee photographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Building photographs, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Photograph of a woman, 1908 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 75th anniversary photo album, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Photograph of Paul Poon Tai Ming, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - 100th anniversary photo booklet, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - CDs of photograph scrapbooks, circa 2003 (Box 6, Folder 17)